

MARIA FELIX

tinywriter77@gmail.com | 631.617.9854

SUMMARY

Corporate communications professional and Emmy Award winning video editor with experience creating and implementing strategic communication plans. Selected by Long Island Business News as one of "Long Island's 40 Rising Stars Under 40" class of 2016.

SKILLS

- INTERNAL COMMUNICATIONS
- COPYWRITING
- VIDEO EDITING
- **EXECUTIVE COMMUNICATIONS**
- MEDIA RELATIONS
- **WEB CONTENT MANAGEMENT**
- CRISIS COMMUNICATIONS

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR EMPLOYEE COMMUNICATIONS SPECIALIST

BAE SYSTEMS • 3/2009 - PRESENT

Internal Communications lead for the Tactical Systems product line and Greenlawn, NY site. Communicate to employees through TAC SYS Tweets, newsletter, email, electronic signage, intranet, and eCards. Lead community relations and philanthropic initiatives. Contribute to social media. Produce Telly award-winning monthly video segment ESSpotlight which highlights employees from across the company who go above and beyond the scope of their responsibilities. Produce Off the Record, a quarterly video series featuring senior leadership as they speak candidly about their personal lives and experiences.

PUBLIC RELATIONS COORDINATOR

BROOKHAVEN HOSPITAL • 8/2007 - 3/2009

Acted as Hospital's spokesperson, photographer, and marketing coordinator. Played an instrumental role in the redesign of the hospital's website and marketing campaign. Authored employee newsletter and weekly message from the President.

MEDIA SPECIALIST

MEMORIAL SLOAN KETTERING CANCER CENTER • 4/2005-8/2007

Wrote press releases and pitched stories to local and national press to promote medical breakthroughs and research results. Handled media relations for the Department of Pediatrics which resulted in national coverage with CNN, Fox News, and the Today Show.

VIDEO EDITOR

NEWS 12 LONG ISLAND • 7/1999 - 4/2005

Edited packages for daily newscasts, working closely with reporters and

EDUCATION

producers. Recognized with an Emmy, Telly, NY Festival, and Folio award for video editing excellence. Trained interns and junior editors. Tuned in microwave and satellite trucks for live feeds.